Drachman-Taylor family papers, 1875-1996
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Drachman-Taylor family papers, 1875-1996
Call Number MS 413
Drachman Family
Papers, 1875-1996 (bulk 1920-1975). This collection is comprised of the papers of John and Rosemary (Drachman) Winchcombe-Taylor. The bulk of the material relates to their lengthy literary careers. The collection includes personal and professional correspondence, published and unpublished manuscripts, short stories, adaptations, plays, articles and speeches. Also included ais research material, legal papers, publicity material, business and personal photographs, negatives and slides, business and personal scrapbooks and recordings of literary events, and personal record albums. The collection also contains a small amount of material relating to other members of the Drachman family.
39 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
Rosemary (Drachman) Winchcombe-Taylor who came from a prominent Arizona pioneer family was born in Phoenix, Arizona and moved to Tucson, AZ as a child. She attended the University of Arizona and went on to graduate from Stanford University with a Bachelor of Arts in 1922. After graduation she traveled to Europe. There she met Floyd Gibbons, an American war correspondent, who helped her begin her literary career as a war correspondent. She traveled with him to Morocco and covered the Riff War for various newspapers including the Tucson Citizen. Ms. Winchcombe-Taylor wrote throughout her childhood and college, but she began publishing while covering the war. In the 1930s she returned to Tucson, AZ and married author John Winchcombe-Taylor in 1934.
John Winchcombe-Taylor, born into an acting family, was an American citizen raised in England. He enlisted in the British military in 1914 and retired as a captain in 1919. In 1924 he returned to the United States. He wrote adventure stories for various magazines in the 1920s and 1930s as well as acted under the stage name Jamison Reilly with his brother.
In 1939 at the start of World War II, Mr. Winchcombe-Taylor joined the Canadian military and served as a training officer before retiring with the rank of Major in 1943. Ms. Winchcombe-Taylor lived alternately between Tucson, AZ and with Mr. Winchcombe-Taylor in Canada. During this time, Ms. Winchcombe-Taylor began work on her first novel, Chicken Every Sunday, which was about her childhood and her mother's business of taking in boarders. The novel became a bestseller and was later adapted for both the stage and film. After the War, the couple returned to Tucson and continued their literary career with Rosemary Winchcombe-Taylor publishing eight novels and a number of short stories and articles. Many were based on her childhood and family. John Winchcombe-Taylor published a historical novel, Ram, and a number of articles, short stories and plays including several based on Ms. Winchcombe-Taylor's books. He also helped organize Vanguard (1944-1948), an association which promoted the interests of Americans who served with British forces in World War I and World War II. Ms. Winchcombe-Taylor wrote under the names of Rosemary Drachman, Rosemary Drake and for her novels, Rosemary Taylor. Mr. Winchcombe-Taylor wrote under the names J. Winchcombe-Taylor and Winchcombe Taylor and acted under the name Jamison Reilly.
Organization
This collection is organized into 7 series, with 16 subseries.
Series 1: Biographical Files, 1912-1981
Series 2: Correspondence: 1875-1979
Subseries: Business, 1942-1979
Subseries: Personal, 1875-1979
Series 3: Writings, 1914-1984
Subseries: Manuscripts, 1943-1975
Subseries: Adaptations, 1943-1970
Subseries: Short Stories, 1927-1956
Subseries: Plays, 1921-1959
Subseries: Articles, 1925-1971
Subseries: Speeches, 1951-1972
Subseries: Research Files, 1932-1963
Subseries: Publicity Files, 1925-1972
Subseries: Miscellaneous, 1914-1984
Series 4: Photographs, Negatives and Slides, 1898-1996
Subseries: Business, 1929-1954
Subseries: Personal, 1898-1996
Series 5: Audio-Visual Materials, 1943-1951
Series 6: Scrapbooks, 1903-1996
Subseries: Business, 1943-1962
Subseries: Personal, 1903-1996
Series 7: Oversize Materials, 1902-1981
Scope and Content Note
Papers, 1875-1996 (bulk 1920-1975). This collection consists of the papers of authors John and Rosemary (Drachman) Winchcombe-Taylor. The bulk of the papers contains personal and professional correspondence, published and unpublished manuscripts, short stories, plays, articles, speeches, and adaptations of their writings. The collection also includes photographs and scrapbooks relating to their personal lives and literary careers. A small amount of material within the collection is related to additional members of the Drachman family, primarily biographical material, correspondence, photographs and scrapbooks. Manuscripts titles often appear in other forms of writing as Rosemary Winchcombe-Taylor's writings were adapted for the stage, film, radio and serials.
Access Terms
Drachman family -- Archives.
Taylor, Rosemary, b. 1899 -- Archives.
Tucson (Ariz.) -- History -- Sources.
Women war correspondents -- Archives.
Container List
- Series 1: Biographical Files, 1912-1981
  This series contains biographical materials associated with John and Rosemary Winchcombe-Taylor. It includes certificates, news clippings, material relating to their estate as well as materials related to the military career of John Winchcombe-Taylor. The "Drachman Family-General" folder contains materials associated with additional members of the Drachman family particularly Rosemary Winchcombe-Taylor's immediate family including Drachman family trees.
  - Drachman Family- General. 1914-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Winchcombe-Taylor- Certificates. 1912-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Winchcombe-Taylor- General. 1922-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Winchcombe-Taylor, John- Estate. 1952-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Winchcombe-Taylor, John- Military. 1917-1921 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Winchcombe-Taylor, John- Military. 1939-1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1875-1979
  This series is divided into two subseries:
  Business (1942-1978) contains correspondence between the Winchcombe-Taylors and various publishers, agents, authors, producers and fans relating to their literary works. Also included is correspondence related to literary research and promotion.
  Personal (1875-1979) contains correspondence primarily between John and Rosemary Winchcombe-Taylor and family, friends and political figures. It also includes correspondence between members of the Drachman family and others. Of note - is correspondence that Rosemary Winchcombe-Taylor wrote that doubled as a personal journal.
  - Subseries: Business, 1942-1978
    - Avon Books. 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bilby, Kenneth. 1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Blassingame, Lurton. 1942-1953 (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
    - Blassingame, Lurton. 1954-1959 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Blassingame, Lurton. 1960-1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Caruso, Joseph. 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Crowell Company. 1947-1960 (Box 1, Folder 18-20)
    - Dodd, Mead and Company. 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Dodds, John. 1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Dodge, Mrs. 1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Epstein, Julius. 1945-1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Fan Mail. 1942-1949 (Box 2, Folder 5-7)
    - Fan Mail. 1950-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Fitzgerald, Louise and Doris West. 1949-1951 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - General. 1943-1951 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - General. 1925-1951 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - General. 1952-1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Goodman, Jules. 1944-1950 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Gross, Edward. 1943-1949 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Gross, Edward. 1950-1960 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Gross, Nelson. 1948 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - G.P. Putnam's Sons. 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Harmon, Charlotte. 1955-1965 (Box 2, Folder 17-19)
    - Henry, Eugene. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Johnston, Albert. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Lee Keedick. 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Lester, William. 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
    - McCormick, Ada. 1959 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - National War Fund. 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Needham, Jane. 1956-1960 (Box 2, Folder 27-29)
    - Nimmer, Melville. 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - O'Melveny, John. 1944-1958 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Promotion- Fraternity Publications. 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Promotion- Looking Up. nd, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Promotion- Looking Up. 1957-1959 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Research. 1951-1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Samuel French. 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Stierhem, Eleanor. 1947-1955 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - St. Martin's Press. 1958-1963 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Strassman, Toni. 1945-1960 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Strassman, Toni. 1961-1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Swanson, H. N. 1949-1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - West-Ways. 1949-1951 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Whittlesey House-McGraw Hill. 1942-1947 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
    - Whittlesey House-McGraw Hill. 1948-1972 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - William Morris Agency. 1943-1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Wood, Audrey. 1944-1965 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Personal. 1875-1979
    - Alan. 1963-1969 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Arizona Historical Foundation. 1960-1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Baldocchi, Maude. 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Bliven, Rose and Bruce. 1966-1973 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Bromiley Family. 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Carlsmith, Peg. 1940-1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence as Journal Entries. 1951-1959 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence as Journal Entries. 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 22-24)
    - Correspondence as Journal Entries. 1963 (Box 3, Folder 25-26)
    - Correspondence as Journal Entries. 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence as Journal Entries. 1964-1969 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence as Journal Entries. 1970-1975 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
    - Dede. 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - De Vault, Robert. 1961-1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Drachman, Ethel. 1875-1945 (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
    - Drachman Family. 1923-1925 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Drachman, Oliver and Family. 1936-1971 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Drachman, Phil and Betty. 1915-1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Fitts, Billy. 1960 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Garfield, Brian. 1965-1972 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - General. 1915-1959 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
    - General. 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - General. 1970-1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Gibbons, Floyd. undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Gjelsness, Rudy and Ruth. 1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Glick, Carl. 1958-1970 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Hayden, Carl. 1939-1957 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Hundevad, John. 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Icks, Robert. 1942-1968 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - McGhee, Joan. 1960-1964 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - McGowan, Katherine. 1959-1971 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Ortega, Anna. 1957-1961 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Partridge Family. 1943-1970 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Shirer Family. 1958-1965 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Snell and Co. 1950 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Switten, Lucie. 1948-1953 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Turner Family. 1973-1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Udall, Morris. 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Whiting Family. 1960-1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Winchcombe-Taylor, John. 1939-1948 (Box 5, Folder 4-11)
    - Winchcombe-Taylor, John. 1950-1967 (Box 5, Folder 12-14)
    - Winchcombe-Taylor, Josephine and Roberta. 1953-1976 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Winchcombe-Taylor, Kathleen. 1955-1970 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Winchcombe-Taylor, Patricia. 1943-1975 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Winchcombe-Taylor, Robert. 1938-1950 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Series 3: Writings, 1914-1984
  This series contains the published and unpublished writings of John and Rosemary Winchcombe-Taylor. The Writings Series is divided into ten subseries:
  Manuscripts (1943-1975) contains drafts and galleys of unpublished and published manuscripts.
  Adaptations (1943-1970) contains film, radio, newspaper and magazine adaptations of several of Rosemary Winchcombe-Taylor's novels. Several adaptations are in foreign languages including German and Spanish.
  Short Stories (1927-1956) contains published and unpublished short stories.
  Plays (1921-1959) contains plays written primarily by John Winchcombe-Taylor. Also included in this subseries are plays adapted from Ms. Winchcombe-Taylor's novels by Mr. Winchcombe-Taylor and other playwrights.
  Articles (1925-1971) contains published and unpublished articles
  Speeches (1951-1972) contains various speeches given by Rosemary Winchcombe-Taylor.
  Research Files (1932-1963) contains research materials with the bulk of the material compiled by John Winchcombe-Taylor.
  Legal Files (1943-1977) contains contracts, copyright and royalty statements.
  Publicity Files (1925-1972) contains publicity material. It includes flyers, biographical statements, lectures series information, publisher catalogs and news clippings.
  Miscellaneous (1914-1984) contains miscellaneous writings, illustrations, book plates, observations and notes. Also includes Rosemary Winchcombe- Taylor's journals
  - Subseries: Manuscripts, 1943-1975
    - 1947 (Box 5, Folder 19-20.)
    - Adrienne -10 Chapters. undated (Box 5, Folder 21-23)
    - Adrienne- 10 Chapters. undated (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Adrienne- 11 Chapters. undated (Box 6, Folder 3-9)
    - Adrienne. 1963 (Box 6, Folder 10-12)
    - Bar Nothing Ranch. 1947 (Box 6, Folder 13-15)
    - Bar Nothing Ranch-Galley. 1948 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Chicken Every Sunday. undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Chicken Every Sunday. 1943 (Box 6, Folder 18-20)
    - Come Clean, My Love. undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Come Clean, My Love. undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Come Clean, My Love-Second Draft. undated (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
    - Could be Right. undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - The Guerilla. undated (Box 7, Folder 5-7)
    - Harem Scare'm. undated (Box 7, Folder 8-12)
    - The King's Vagabond. undated (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
    - The King's Vagabond. 1962 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Laird and Colonel Anne. undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Laird and Colonel Anne. 1963 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Laird and Colonel Anne-Version 1. undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Laird and Colonel Anne-Version 3. undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Laird and Colonel Anne-Version 4. undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Little Arthur. undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Little Arthur. undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Looking Up. undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Looking Up. 1957 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
    - Looking Up-Chapters. 1957 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Memoirs of Monsieur D'Artagnan. undated (Box 8, Folder 6-10)
    - Memoirs of Monsieur D'Artagnan. 1945 (Box 8, Folder 11-13)
    - Now I'm Mrs. Chicken. undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Now I'm Mrs. Chicken. 1949 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Penelope. undated (Box 8, Folder 16-20)
    - Penelope. undated (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - Penelope. 1963-1969 (Box 9, Folder 4-6)
    - Penelope. 1975 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
    - Ram. undated (Box 9, Folder 9-18)
    - Ram. undated (Box 10, Folder 1-6)
    - Ram-Galley. undated (Box 10, Folder 7-9)
    - Ram- Original. undated (Box 10, Folder 10-13)
    - Ram. 1960 (Box 10, Folder 14-17)
    - Ridin' the Rainbow. 1943 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Ridin' the Rainbow. 1943 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Ridin' the Rainbow. 1944 (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
    - Summertime Wives. undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - The Town's Coming This Way. undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Tucson, Tenants and Typewriters. 1970 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Untitled. 1960-1961 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Subseries: Adaptations, 1943-1970
    - Broadway in a Barn. 1957 (Box 11, Folder 8-9)
    - Chicken Every Sunday. 1943 (Box 11, Folder 10-11)
    - Chicken Every Sunday-Film. 1945 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Chicken Every Sunday-German Serial. 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 13-14)
    - Chicken Every Sunday-Spanish Version. 1944 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Chicken Every Sunday -Radio. 1949 (Box 11, Folder 16-17)
    - Harem Scare'm. 1951 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Harem Scare'm-Serial. 1951 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Ridin' the Rainbow. 1944 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Ridin' the Rainbow-Spanish Version. 1946 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Sunny-The Spirit of '76. 1947 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Subseries: Short Stories, 1927-1956
    - Abdel Krim on the American Aviators. undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Aces. 1931 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Adventure. 1940 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - An American Affair of Maturity. undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Air! undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Alibi. 1934 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - All-Fiction. 1931 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - The Ambivalent Mr. Hauser. 1956 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - And so we are Landlords. undated (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Battle Birds. 1933 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Battle Stories. 1931 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Breakfast with a Cowboy. undated (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - But we don't think so Fast. undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Caprice Value. undated (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Children for John. undated (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Cleopatra and the Asp. undated (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Conflict. 1933 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Cowboy Lover. undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Cowboy Stories. 1934 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Daughters of Death. 1935 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Deadheads. 1939 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Detective Fiction Weekly. 1934 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Eagles of the Air. 1930 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Farewell to a Soldier. undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - A Female Bandit. 1938 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Fiesta in the Desert. undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Fifty-Fifty is all Wrong. undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Film Agents. undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Film Crowds. undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - A Flight in Morocco. undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Footlights. undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Gabe Blows his Horn. undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - General. undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - The Girl in Soft Focus. undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - He Trains Fleas. undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - High-Seas Adventures. 1934 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - I give you Iceland, Yank. undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - International Detective Magazine. 1933 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - It Happened like This. undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - It's a Nice Clean Business. 1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 24-25)
    - John April. undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Landlady Plus. undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Laurels for Casey. undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - A Life in My Hands. undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Love in a Ghost Town. undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - The Lone Eagle. 1934-1936 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - A Man worth Fighting For. 1947 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Meet My Ancestor. undated (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Men are where you find them. undated (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Moroccan Moon. undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Mother's Boarders. undated (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Mrs. Duncan Keeps on Deciding. undated (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Navy Stories. 1929 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Old Grumpy. undated (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - On Onions and a Horse Ridden Backwards. undated (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - One Way to Become and Author. undated (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - The Open Road for Boys. 1927-1928 (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - Opus Six. undated (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Peraltareavis, Baron of Arizona. undated (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - Pinafore Pirates. undated (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - Pioneer Love. undated (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Pirate Stories. 1935 (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - Powder for Lille. undated (Box 12, Folder 48)
    - Pushing Mother out of the Nest. undated (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Rediwill Saves the Boy. undated (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - The Royal Tank Corps Journal. 1931-1934 (Box 12, Folder 51-52)
    - Scotland Yard. 1931 (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - Single Standard. undated (Box 12, Folder 54)
    - Sky Fighters. 1934-1940 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Sky Riders. 1931 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - So Maybe you'd like to be a Mailman. undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - So you want to Rent a House. undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Spy Stories. 1929 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - The State I'm In. undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Sure-Fire Western. 1938 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - The Taking of Corporal John. undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - The Tank. 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 10-11)
    - Thrilling Adventures. 1934-1939 (Box 13, Folder 12-14)
    - Top-Notch. 1936 (Box 13, Folder 15-16)
    - War Novels. 1928-1930 (Box 13, Folder 17-20)
    - War Stories. 1927-1932 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - War Stories. 1927-1932 (Box 14, Folder 1-5)
    - Western Romances. 1936 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - A Yank with the Terriers. undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Your Husband and your Girlfriend. undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - You've got to run for first Base. undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - The Zero Hour. 1928 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Subseries: Plays, 1921-1959
    - Arizona Comedy. undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Bar Nothing Ranch. 1953 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Be my Love. undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - The Broom-maker. undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - The Broom-maker-Johann. undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Chicken Every Sunday. undated (Box 14, Folder 16-17)
    - Come Clean, My Love-Version 1. undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Come Clean, My Love-Version 2. undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Come Clean, My Love-Version 4. undated (Box 14, Folder 20-21)
    - Come Clean, My Love. 1949 (Box 14, Folder 22-23)
    - Come Clean, My Love. 1951 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Consider the Lily. 1934 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
    - Dar Tazi. 1930 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Easy Street, West. undated (Box 15, Folder 4-5)
    - Eternal Summer. undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Eternal Summer. 1950 (Box 15, Folder 7-10)
    - Eternal Summer-Draft 1. undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Footlights and Sixguns. undated (Box 15, Folder 12-18)
    - General. undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - A German Soldier. undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - The Great Conspiracy. 1922 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Harem Scare'm. undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - The O'Donoghue. undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Porky and Peroxide. 1921 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Randalin's Crowning. 1922 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Ridin' the Rainbow. undated (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Riding the Rainbow. 1959 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - The Ring of Death. undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - A Son of his Father. 1926 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Sweethearts and Wives. undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Terry of Tralee. undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Up on a Ladder. 1922 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - You're Never Through. undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Subseries: Articles, 1925-1971
    - An American Woman in Tangier. undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - And Why Not? 1943 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Cabeza de Vaca: First across the Continent. undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Chicken comes home to Roost. undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Cinderella on Broadway. 1952 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Dogs that have Owned Me. undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - England's Rock. undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Entertaining without Money. undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Excerpt. 1971 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Ex-Spinster Eats Crow. undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Feminism in Morocco by War's End. undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - The First Lady of Fez is an American. 1926 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - From Tamales to "Chicken." undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Girl Describes Land of Riffs. 1925 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Harem Episode. undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Harems and Husbands. undated (Box 16, Folder 21)